we're going to start off by talking
about art and photography do you like
art H that's interesting um depends on
what I like Cinema for instance movies
music but I don't know too much about um
paintings or Modern Art I'm not too
familiar with so it depends on what kind
of art do you like to take photographs
yes I wouldn't say the photographs are
good but I do enjoy taking pictures yeah
do you prefer to take photos of yourself
or other things of other things it's
kind of hard to take pictures of
yourself unless it's a selfie and that's
limited so pictures of other things
mostly now let's talk about animals do
you like animals I love animals uh land
animals friendly so to speak animals not
insects and not anything from the ocean
what is your favorite animal um probably
a dog dogs for obvious reasons you can
keep them as pets in terms of like
non-domesticated animals probably
Jaguars do you have any animals in your
home as pets yes I have two dogs they're
both from the shelter the animal shelter
they rescues um yeah I've always had
pets our family really likes keeping
animals right ground now let's talk
about bags what type of bags do you like
I
prefer purses that are a little bit on
the larger side just cuz I like to put
every thing of my life in my purse um so
it ends up weighing maybe 20
kilos yeah larger bags probably
structured larger bags how often do you
carry a bag when you go out every day I
think that's the case for most women I
think they carry a bag every even if you
go down to the grocery or the
supermarket you take your bag with you
usually
right what sort of bags do women like to
buy it
depends um it depends on your outfit it
depends on where you're going um for the
day if you're going to the office you
probably want something bigger that can
fit your laptop your phone
paperwork um everything that you might
need during the day um if it's nighttime
you'd want something smaller like a
clutch something more Sleek
elegant um so it depends if you're
traveling you'd want a much bigger bag
that's able to fit mhm not just you but
all of your family's stuff as well so
everything women like all kinds of bags
that's why we have so many of them now
let's talk about birthday mhm what did
you usually do on your birthday when you
were a child so when I was a kid when I
was a child um in school we had a
uniform everybody wore a uniform to
school so when it was your birthday it
was the one day of the year that you
were allowed to wear whatever you wanted
so it was a big deal I mean at least I
would pick out my outfit like two months
in advance it would be like a little
dress like a princessy frock matching
shoes matching accessories for your hair
and then you would take some kind of
chocolate or candy to school and then
you could take like a period off and go
and give the candy out to other teachers
and other kids in the school and we
looked forward to it every year it was
the highlight to get to not have to wear
the uniform to wear whatever you wanted
and to basically be able to skip class
and go out and hand out chocolates cuz
it's your birthday how do you normally
celebrate your birthday now H very
differently everyone's allowed to wear
whatever they want now so it's kind of
not doesn't have the same charm um it
depends I like to do a little dinner
with um my friends something lowkey I'm
not a very big party person so dinner is
usually good um followed by probably
like a games night or a movies movie
night at home or at the cinema something
low key do you think it's important to
give someone a card on their birthday
like a handwritten like a birthday
card um I think so yes because I'm quite
sentimental and emotional so I prefer
more um emotional sentimental gifts so I
think if someone takes the time to write
something by hand for you I think that I
mean I hold on to stuff like that so I
think it's a very nice thoughtful
present to give someone on their
birthday the first time I met a new
friend so I'm going to go way back it
was my first day of school
kindergarten and I met a girl named Aman
prit k um she we were about I think we
just turned four years old uh we met
obviously in
kindergarten um first year of school uh
what I liked about her when I first saw
her I mean we were sitting together with
the teacher made us sit next to each
other and um she had this long
hair and it was like sectioned into two
parts and it was just braided all the
way
down and she had the cutest face I've
ever seen she had this little fluffy
marshmallow like face I guess that's all
it takes when you're a kid to want to be
friends with somebody um and then I
tried tried to so there's like this
little thing that kids do where they put
their thumb out to show other kids that
I want to be your
friend um and then if you don't want to
be friends with them you do this it's
like a silly little thing so I did this
to her I put my thumb out to say hey do
you want to be
friends and she was like this and I was
heartbroken I was like how can she know
want to be my
friend um and then I saw her again the
next day
um and the day the next day after that
and the day after that and then
eventually we ended up becoming best
friends she she did it back to me
obviously at some point she was my first
best friend that I ever had in life she
was from Punjab which is a part of
India um and her mom used to make the
most amazing it's called parata it's
like this
stuffed bread it's like they put a
potato and spices into like um into a
flatbread and my mom used to make
something called CRA which is sweet
semolina situation that's the end of the
two minutes okay we've been talking
about a friend that you met we're going
to now talk about friends at school how
important is it for children to have
lots of friends at school to thank you
for watching this video I want to give
you a free course that has help
thousands of students improve their I
speaking score what it's going to do is
take you through every single part of
the test and give you strategies for
part one part two and part three and
also allow you to practice at home for
free and get feedback to sign up for
that for free all you have to do is just
click the link in the description thanks
very much and let's get back to the
video it depends I would say I would
perhaps think that quality is more
important than quantity so I wouldn't
say that the objective should be to make
as many friends as you can or to be
popular um as much as the objective
should be to build meaningful
friendships with people that could be
one person that could be five people
that could be 10 people situational I
would say yeah so it's not so much how
many friends you have as um it's it's
not as important to have a lot of
friends as it might be to have people
that you can trust that you can kind of
take with you in life for a longer term
do you think it is wrong for parents to
choose which friends their children have
H again that's a tricky one now when I
answer these questions I'm thinking back
to real life situations and in some
cases I have seen parents
interfering and trying to make those
decisions for their children where they
were right to do so because the child
was in bad company and they were too
naive or too um I mean I guess they were
just too naive to see that that
situation was not right for them but
their parent obviously was able to
identify that my child's in Bad Company
so in those cases I would say that your
parents are able to read a dangerous
situation better but there's also the
flip side
where everybody kind of does make bad
decisions your parents made bad
decisions you made bad decisions and the
way that you learn from them is to have
a negativist experience and then find
your way out of it um so I would say
that I can see certain situations
whether it's bad relationships bad
friendships um when you're younger not
relationships when you're younger
friendships when you're younger some
times it's necessary to have that
experience so that you know firsthand
how to deal with that situation and you
may not be able to get that experience
if your parents always Shield you from
every single thing that can go wrong so
I can kind of see depends on the
situation I would say now let's talk
about making new friends can you think
of any disadvantages of making new
friends online disadvantages of making
new friends online I think the I think
there's more disadvantages to
making new friends I mean there was a
Show recently that came out on Netflix
called tender swindler the thing is with
most of what we see online isn't real
whether it's social media or um even
news for that matter uh everything is
kind of edit edited and monitored to
present a certain kind of
image so if you meet somebody online and
you know nothing about them they can
really present any version of reality or
a completely um
curated sometimes dishonest form of
their reality to you so it's a very
dangerous uh game to play friendships or
relationships both friendships
friendships yeah
it's somebody you know nothing about is
a very
everything can go wrong there right
would you say it is harder for people to
make new friends as they get older
yes I think it becomes harder for people
to
make um friends as they get
older I think adults are perhaps a
little bit
more
um more structured I mean the older that
you get the more set you get in your
ways your routine where you work your
family your gym children for children it
becomes it's very easy for children to
interact with other children like if you
put two kids in a room and 3 seconds
they're talking to each other without
any restriction they're talking about
all of their family secrets and
everything you know they they're
comfortable but with adults obviously
people tend to be more filtered when
they interact with other
adults um also I think if you've been
friends from the time that you were a
child with somebody you've lived through
so many life events together that that
kind of bond is hard to build with
someone that you meet in your mid 30s
because you've just lost so much time
that you're learning something you're
learning about them from scratch where
they went to school about their family
about their relationships about their
siblings so yeah I think it's a it's not
impossible you can make a lot of
incredible friendships
later in life but it's probably harder
to come by than if you were a kid in
play school so what I'm going to do now
is give you feedback on each part cuz
each part is a little bit different give
you some tips on on on how to perform as
well or even better um next time and
then there are four marking criteria uh
fluency and coherence grammar
pronunciation and vocabulary and and I
will give you a band for each of those
and tell you what band the top is band
nine so let's see if you can get get
right to the top to thank you for making
it this far in the video I want to give
you 10% off our VIP course I VIP course
is the most successful I course in the
world that is a fact because we have
more band seven eight and nine success
stories than any other I course in the
entire world we do that by simplifying
the whole I process support supporting
you with some of the best ises teachers
in the world and being with you every
step of the way until you get the score
that you need all you have to do is just
look down in the description just click
that and you can sign up if you have any
questions about the VIP course always
feel free to get in touch with us we
answer 100% of the questions that we get
hope that you become a VIP if not enjoy
the rest of this free video so part one
it's just normal everyday questions and
you answer those very very naturally
again it was like talking to a friend or
a colleague and the length of your
answers was also quite good this is not
a criticism and it's just kind of who
you are as a person you're a very
friendly chatty person who wants the
other person to interact so you're often
like girls like buying bags right that
is fine in normal conversation if you
were to do the test for real The
Examiner could be quite stone-faced cuz
they're doing their job they're not
being unfriendly they just have a job to
do and they're trying to think about
your grammar and your vocabulary and
your pronunciation and your fluency and
there's a lot going on there and for
them they cannot start to interact with
you yeah and on test day you might not
get a very friendly examiner like me I
don't know whether I was friendly or you
were but they might be like you know
don't do that or some of them could you
know be having a bad day and they just
like don't ask questions now I have
experienced with with not myself but
other students have said when they did
that they thought the examiner was
criticizing them or being rude they took
that to heart and thought Oh my God I
failed my test and they went from doing
very very well to everything fell apart
because if you feel nervous yeah you
feel uncomfortable with someone then it
really affects your fluency you can clam
up you don't want to really show your
language and who you are you don't want
to because one of the Great
uh advantages or or great strength that
you have is you you you're very open
about about who you are as a person and
that's great because it allows you to
speak in a very fluent way if you go and
do the test for real probably don't
interact with the examiner as much part
two you did a great job because you just
picked a real event a real person from
your life and it's much easier to talk
about that some students try to pick
something high level or impr impressive
to impress The Examiner there's no such
thing uh the best thing to do is pick
something from your real life cuz that's
easy to talk about part three you did
very very well because you really
extended your answers again you use real
situations from your own life you don't
have to do that but it really did help
you develop your answers terms of the
scores pronunciation is pretty much
Perfect The Examiner will be thinking
about can I understand every word this
person is saying 100% I can understand
every syllable then the examiner will be
thinking about highlevel pronunciation
features such as your intonation so our
voices go up or voices go down you speak
like a native English speaker in that
respect sentence stress is when we
emphasize certain words this is my phone
not your phone so you emphasize certain
words at times again you do that 100%
naturally and then you use connected
speech the way native English speakers
talk we wouldn't say I want to talk
about my friend he say I want to talk
about my friend the flow of the language
so absolutely perfect no problems there
coherence and fluency coherence is did
you answer the questions did you develop
them enough you did that 100% of the
time and then fluency is did you speak
without any um unnatural pausing you did
pause at times but the reason why you
paused is important so in the last I
think it was the second last question
you were talking about adults and you
were saying their lives are
more structured so you weren't trying to
think of the correct vocabulary because
your English isn't good enough you were
trying to just formulate your thoughts
and come up with the appropriate precise
word which you did so that demonstrates
to The Examiner that you have a very
high level of vocabulary cuz if you were
cuz you're trying to think of the what's
the word what so when people don't
really know the language then they would
stop and also because you approach this
not as a test but more as a conversation
and you are very open and talk about
your your life in a very open way that
really helps with fluency so again top
marks for for fluency and coherence
grammar I didn't hear a single grammar
mistake The Examiner will be thinking
about the accuracy of your grammar did
you make any mistakes and the range of
your grammar so if I talk to you about a
birthday party in the past did you use
the appropriate past tenses and then I
asked you about what do you do today did
you switch tenses did you use the
appropriate grammatical structures and
tenses to talk about it each situation
and again you did that perfectly
vocabulary very natural you use a nice
mixture of just normal everyday words
which everybody uses and you also use
idiomatic language very very well so as
you can see you're using very natural
English and overall you would get a
perfect band line oh wow which is very
rare oh wow very very rare so well done
thank you